# **Job Guiyab**

Mobile +971 52 444 6708 B36, Apartment 114, Al Khail Gate 1 Al Quoz, Dubai, UAE

Email: job.quiyab@outlook.com



### **OBJECTIVE**

To obtain an organizational position where there is a room for advancement and personal growth related to my educational background and professional experience.

## **PROFILE**

A highly resourceful, dedicated with strong work ethic and able to motivate staff to perform to their maximum potential. With an in depth experience on Bar and Restaurant Operation, P&L, costing, staffing, cost control and pre-opening. Exceptional organizational and planning skills; adaptable and enjoy new challenges. Possess required communication skills, approachable, friendly and proven to create a guest memorable experience.

## **Area of Expertise**

- Bar & Restaurant Management
- Pre Opening
- Stock Control
- Staff Development

- Price Strategies
- Guest Retention
- Innovative Business
- Promotional Ideas
- Menu Engineering
- Event Planning

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

December 2019 - July 2021

**Director of Food and Beverage** Widus Hotel & Casino Clark, Philippines

### **Key Accomplishment**

- Trained, coached and mentored staff to ensure smooth adoption of new programs as well as old. Ensured high standards of food and beverage quality, service and marketing to maximize profits and ensure outstanding customer service.
- Implemented departmental strategies and maximized the financial performance of departments by increasing covers of 9.23% and department profit revenue of 5.61%.
- Managed annual budget by maintaining appropriate inventory and staffing levels.
- Introduced new beverage and food menu alongside with Executive Chef which increased over all revenue by 2.73% compared to budget and 7.13% compared to previous year.
- Improved total food and beverage costs by through menu engineering and instituting new inventory control measures. Trained all managers to maximize existing system to control and reduce over-all beverage cost to 19.64%.
- Develop and implement re opening guidelines and safety measures for Food and Beverage.

Cluster Food and Beverage Manager DoubleTree by Hilton Doha – Al Saad & Aleph Residences Curio Collection by Hilton West Bay, Doha, Qatar

# **Key Accomplishment**

- Created operational manual and standard operating procedure for each outlet.
- Analyzed market need for both hotel guests and the local market, monitoring and analyzing
  the activities and trends of competitive restaurants and bar where we based our pricing
  strategy.
- Created a pre-opening training plan and development programs to improve personal or department standards liaising closely with the Training Manager.
- Established departmental manning and hire based nationality and gender ratio.
- Developed beverage and food offering for all Outlets based on each concept and an event specific menu alongside with Executive Chef.
- Sourced suppliers and approved uniform designs based on Outlet concept and lead the team go green and sustainability initiatives.
- Established pre-opening budget and expenses, source out all OS&E for each Food and Beverage Outlet.

February 2016 - June 2019

**Restaurant General Manager** Jumeirah Mina A' Salam Hotel The Arabian Resort, Dubai

# **Key Accomplishment**

- Maintained expense below budget and through accurate planning, purchasing, waste reduction and cost effective procedure which we achieve an average of 23.9% on overall cost.
- Maximized profitability of the Outlet by increasing turnover (revenue and covers)
  as a first priority and controlling costs as a second priority with a 25% increase on covers and
  Restaurant utilization.
- Develop and introduced new beverage menus to all outlet, trained and develop bartenders and service staff.
- Lead the team in food tasting, cocktail and wine list development, created interactive menu both food and beverage which increase guest and staff engagement.
- Enhanced and developed brunch concept including food and beverage offering.
- Responsible for all Health and Safety in the restaurant and ensured that all H&S guidelines are maintained and regular audits on H&S and Fire Safety are in place with a Grade A in audits.
- Inspire a first class team to deliver excellence, consistency, quality and guest experience where it reflect in hotel customers survey by achieving 92.5% and consistent average score of 97% in mystery dinner.
- Developed and successfully implemented marketing plan for the entire year.
- Lead on sales initiative to promote restaurants by featuring the signature dishes and beverage in Lounges to create awareness to hotel guest.
- Forecast daily, weekly and monthly in advance for both revenue and products and achieve an average of -/+5% accuracy.
- Achieved a low staff turnover of 10% in comparison to 20% on previous calendar year.

**Beverage Manager** Jumeirah Restaurant Group Dubai, U.A.E

## **Key Accomplishment**

- Successfully re launched Bahri Bar, Beach Lounge and Segreto Lounge with new menu concept.
- Manages all aspects of beverage ordering, inventory, cost controls and pricing and maintained an average of 19.2% cost.
- Deliver margins in line with budgets and to have an understanding of the financial targets and motivate the staff to achieve them.
- Developed and created training materials for beverage service which created awareness and confidence of staff. Lead training either internally or by sourcing external training.
- Set up bar business in promotions, events and deals and to maintain a dialogue with suppliers which helped the venue to increase footfall and maintained costs.
- Trained all Restaurant General Managers, created awareness and a better understanding on Food and Beverage Cost for standalone and hotel restaurant.

January 2014 – October 2014	<b>Assistant Beverage Manager</b> Jumeirah Mina A Salam Hotel The Arabian Resort, Dubai
November 2012 – December 2013	<b>Assistant Outlet Manager</b> Jumeirah Mina A 'Salam Hotel The Arabian Resort, Dubai
December 2010 – November 2012	<b>Assistant Bars Manager</b> Raffles Dubai
September 2009 – December 2010	Assistant Restaurant Manager (Multi Outlet) Pre- Opening Cabana Restaurant & Lounge NA3NA3 All Day Dining & Ember Grill & Lounge The Address Dubai Mall Hotel
November 2008 – September 2009	<b>Assistant Outlet Manager</b> Beach House Cabana Emirates Leisure Retail
September 2007 – November 2008	<b>F&amp;B Supervisor</b> (Pre-Opening) Raffles Dubai
July 2004 – September 2007	<b>Team Leader &amp;</b> Departmental Trainer Koubba Bar& Armoury Lounge
	Toscana Restaurant

(Pre-Opening)
Madinat Jumeirah

The Arabian Resort, Dubai

June 2002 - July 2004

**Bartender** 

Makati Shangri-La Hotel, Philippines

September 1999 – March 2002

**In-Store-Trainer Bartender** TGIFridays, Philippines

## **EDUCATIONAL ATTAINMENT**

1997 - 2000 Jose Rizal University **Bachelor of Commercial Science - Management** 

### **SKILLS**

Computer Literacy

- Microsoft Office
   MS Word &Excel
- PowerPointEMC & FMCAdaco

- RESPAK
- Microsoft Outlook

SevenRooms

## TRAINING AND SEMINAR ATTENDED

- Wine and Spirits Education Trust, Intermediate, Level 2
- Restaurant Revenue Management, Cornell University
- Hygiene Person in Charge Certificate, Highfield Awarding Bodies, EMEA
- Brandy Classics Introduction Course
- Group Training Skills Workshop

## **CHARACTER REFERENCE**

• Available upon request